最后几段视频已经变得很难理解，需要很多
concentration and patience to understand them.
因此，我很高兴我们现在可以继续利用演习中的网络挑战。
protostar, which will be a lot easier because we have to establish some basics first.
让我们快速了解一下网络级别
0.
The description says you have to convert strings to little endian integers.
这个级别很容易，但是要完全理解发生了什么，代码是
not quite enough.
I show you why.
所以main调用一个函数后台进程，并将其传递一个名称、用户和组
ID it will run with.
But this function is not a common libc function.
您还可以检查/etc/passwd中的用户ID 999，您会发现没有这样的用户ID
user.
This might seem weird but just don’t think so abstractly about computers.
在Linux系统上拥有用户意味着什么？
最后，用户只是一个ID、内存中的一个数字，例如文件的所有者。
just means that this file has this number as owner set.
现在，如果用户列在/etc/passwd文件中，Linux将非常好，并显示
name instead of the number, but under the hood it is still just an integer.
So even though there is no name assigned to that ID, you are still free to use it.
Anyway, back to the code.
The other functions such as serve_forever and set_io are also not known functions.
And when you look at the includes, you will notice that it references a common.c file.
所以这个挑战的作者在一个不同的文件中实现了很多代码，
we don’t know what it does.
But one function is here, and that is the run() function.
You can see that it is called at the end of main().
Run generated a random number, tells us that you should send that number as little endian.
然后执行从文件描述符读取，在本例中是从标准输入读取，解释
this input as a number and compares if it’s the same as the random number before.
So just a simple test.
正如我之前所说，我们可以在不知道下面这些未知功能的情况下解决这个挑战
，因为仅仅阅读注释和函数名就可以告诉我们需要知道的一切，
but as you know, we are not satisfied on this channel when we ignore underlying concepts.
We want to understand computers better.
这些函数实现了这里提到的两个有趣的概念，一个正在运行
the process as a daemon, and the other one is about networking and sockets.
那么我们如何才能弄清楚它的作用呢？
Well we know already everything we need, to be able to reverse engineer this.
So let’s start by exploring the behaviour of the program before digging deeper.
When you try to run the program, nothing happens.
But when you look at the running processes you can see that net0 is already running.
所以让我们快速切换到根用户，这样我们就可以终止该进程并启动它。
ourselves.
The default root password for this VM is “godmode”.
Now we can kill net0 and we can verify that it is not running anymore.
So, let’s execute it again.
什么都没发生？
But if we check the processes we can see that it’s running again.
那发生了什么？
Let’s kill it again and start it with strace.
所以最后是一个出口，但是之前发生了什么？
It seems to open a net0.pid file with write permissions.
Then it changes the user and group id to 999 with set effective uid and gid.
因此，这意味着进程将删除它的根权限，即uid 1向下到用户
id 999.
After that it calls clone().
The manpages says that clone creates a new process similar to fork.
So this will spawn a new process as a clone, a copy, of itself.
返回值是这个新进程的进程ID，等于这个值
written into the .pid file.
So that file just helps you keeping track of the new process you created.
And after that the parent process exits and leaves the child process orphaned.
这就是所谓的孤立过程，因为我们是故意这样做的。
we also refer to this now as a daemon.
It’s now a background process.
所以我们可以做的是，使用-f标志运行strace，跟踪创建的子进程
instead of staying in the parent process.
当我们这样做时，我们看到在克隆之后，我们附加到新的进程和
background the old process exits.
然后我们更改目录并打开/dev/null，这是另一个特殊的伪文件，
acts like a blackhole.
然后我们复制这个过程的stdinput、stdoutput和stderror，基本上
means we bend all these standard streams to point into the blackhole.
Basically we just throw away anything.
然后，我们将子进程ID写入之前具有文件描述符的.pid文件。
number 3.
Now the fun part starts, a new socket is created.
套接字用于网络通信，您可以选择哪种套接字
want with those flags and settings.
但最重要的是调用bind，它试图将这个进程绑定到
the port 2999.
这意味着如果操作系统接收到一个想要建立连接的包
在这个过程中，它会这样做，然后将包含数据的包转发到
process.
但是！，此函数调用失败，因为地址和端口已被另一个使用
Which makes sense because we called net0 already way earlier.
So let’s kill the process again and retry this.
可以！
This looks great.
现在我们监听我们打开的端口，等待接收到的数据包到达。
syscall.
So let’s open a second terminal and use netstat to find this listening process.
And here it is.
On port 2999 the process net0 is listening.
Cool.
Now let’s use netcat to establish a TCP connection with this port.
This will cause the accept call to return, because a new connection got established.
在接受之后，您会立即看到另一个克隆调用，这将创建另一个进程。
to now handle this server-client connection.
这样，另一个用户也可以建立连接，并且不必等到
you are done, because you have now your own dedicated process.
Also accept returned a new filedescriptor that references this socket.
就像常规文件一样，您现在可以用这个文件描述符执行读写操作，比如
you would with any other file.
The kernel underneath makes sure to send the data you write as a TCP packet to the client.
And when it receives data it will make sure that you can read it from this socket.
所以现在它将把std输入、输出和错误流从/dev/null更改为新的
filedescriptor.
And the program can then just read from stdinput and will read the data you sent it.
And that is what the run function does.
如果您将run与最后两个syscall进行比较，我们首先对stdout进行了一次写入，它是
from this printf here, and then an fread from stdin and this is where we are right now.
当我们现在在netcat中键入一行时，netcat将通过
the network to the program, the server.
在服务器端，您可以看到它读取您发送给它的字符串，然后
performed the write telling you that it is the wrong number.
That’s the failed printf in run().
So let’s summarize what the hidden code is doing.
It first deamonizes by cloning itself and killing the parent, to become an orphan.
Then it starts listening on port 2999 for TCP connections.
一旦建立了连接，我们将详细了解TCP协议
other time, it will create another clone of the process to handle this established connection.
While the parent is ready again to accept another connection in parallel.
The child process that handles the connection is now basically just calling run().
所以简单地说，程序作为一个后台进程运行
run() for every client that connects to it.
令人惊叹的！
We understood that.
Now let’s solve the challenge.
First of all we need to get the string representation of that number.
We can use python for that, specifically the struct package - which we already used before.
So with struct.pack we can convert a number to the byte string representation.
But as you can see, the resulting string doesn’t use characters we can type with the keyboard.
我们可以用echo和-e打印这些字节值，但简单地将其导入nc并不能
work, because the number is randomized.
But we can use a simple trick.
我们可以使用echo-e，但在引号中，我们使用反勾号来执行cat的减号，
它只是将我们键入的任何内容重新定向到输出，然后将输出放置
in the quotes of echo.
所以当我们现在把它输入netcat时，我们看到了数字，cat正在等待输入，我们
使用python转换数字，然后简单地将转义字符串粘贴回
另一个终端，点击回车，然后使用ctrl+d，表示我们已经完成了输入。
which closes cat and echo will send the string to netcat.
And that works, we get the sucess “thank you sir/madam message”.